Aleksandr Suprun

Senior DevOps

Summary

Tech stack: AWS, Linux, Python, Bash, GitLab CI/CD, Jenkins, PostgreSQL, nginx, Ansible, Terraform, Kubernetes

July 2023 — October 2023

London, Great Britain

I'm a highly motivated IT professional with a strong passion for technology, which has fueled my successful career. Committed to continuous learning, I actively seek opportunities to improve my skills by reading specialized literature and participating in IT communities. This helps me share my expertise and gain insights from industry peers. 🌟

My interests include application security, artificial intelligence, and Telegram bot development. I hold certifications in AWS and HashiCorp. and I'm currently working towards Kubernetes certification to deepen my cloud orchestration skills. I also have a strong interest in Infrastructure as Code and observability. 📜 🧠 🐍

I use arch with i3wm, btw 💻

Experience

Sweatcoin

DevOps Engineer https://sweatco.in

- Developed and implemented a monitoring system for critical systems in Consul. Exported check results to Alertmanager with notifications in Slack. Constructed a dashboard in Grafana.
- Introduced a Grafana provisioning system using config files.
- Enhanced existing and introduced new Ansible roles.
- Architected and implemented a Jenkins pipeline for test automation, deploying infrastructure in AWS through a combination of AWS CLI and Terraform.
- Crafted Bash scripts to automate various tasks.

Appello Software

DevOps Engineer https://appello.com.au/

- Reduced the company's AWS costs by 15%.
- Built a monitoring system utilizing Grafana, Prometheus, and CloudWatch.
- Optimized CI/CD processes, resulting in a 40% reduction in median build time.
- Created Terraform modules for deploying environments.
- Developed Ansible roles, Bash, and Python scripts for various automation tasks.
- Conducted training seminars for colleagues from other departments.
- Held the position of DevOps team lead.
- Worked with AWS: EC2, ECS, EKS, RDS, ECR, Route53, IAM, Cloudfront, CloudWatch, CloudTrail, S3

RT Labs DevOps Engineer

https://rtlabs.ru/

March 2020 — August 2021 Moscow, Russia

Chestny Znak

Linux Engineer

November 2018 — February 2020 Moscow, Russia

September 2021 — July 2023

Sydney, Australia

- Prepared the pre-production environment in a private cloud.
- Developed Ansible roles for automating management and updates of software products.
- Worked with a private cloud on VMware, including development and staging environments.
- Engaged in optimizing the Nginx proxy.
- Created GitLab CI pipelines.
- Automated various tasks by writing scripts in Bash and Python.
- Documented the software product update process.
- Interacted with related departments and contractors.

https://chestnyznak.ru/en/

- Worked as part of the on-call shift as a Linux engineer.
- Managed the company's infrastructure, consisting of 1200+ servers across three data centers.
- Developed pipelines in GitLab.
- Wrote Ansible roles.
- Automated the process of updating data in FreeIPA using Python.
- Monitored infrastructure metrics and responded to alerts.
- Conducted troubleshooting of incidents.
- Participated in the update of the company's network equipment.

Education

42

Nov 2018 - Nov 2019

Juneway.pro

Dec 2019 - Nov 2020

http://www.42.fr/

Learned C programming, basic Linux admin skills through extensive training. Explored programming concepts, hands-on coding, debugging. Understand Linux OS - installation, configuration, administration.

https://juneway.pro

Graduated DevOps course, hands-on deploying Django app (Docker, Postgres, nginx) in Gitlab-CI, strong container deployment & app management grasp. Deployed GCP infra with Ansible/Terraform. Also, set up KubeSpray Kubernetes cluster.

Certifications

HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003)

HashiCorp

https://shorturl.at/hBPQ2

June 2023

AWS Knowledge: Architecting

Amazon Web Services Training and Certification

https://shorturl.at/lyFZ6

AWS Knowledge: Amazon EKS

Amazon Web Services (AWS) https://shorturl.at/eqvw1 January 2024

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Amazon Web Services (AWS)

January 2024

June 2023

https://shorturl.at/npHX6